Finding Aid for General Television Network records, 1954-1997
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
General Television Network records 1954-1997
General Television Network.
3 oversize volumes
11 linear feet (in 12 boxes)
2008179 Bb 2
Television production and post-production company located in Oak Park, Michigan. The record group consists primarily of albums containing photographs, correspondence, clippings and other materials documenting GTN, its facilities, staff, and projects.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was donated by Joan Akers Binkow in October 2008 (donor no. 10120 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
In 1957, Stanley Akers created Giant View Television, predecessor to General Television Network (GTN), renamed in 1960. GTN grew out of manufacturing and steel stamping, and began by producing metal casings for the first TV projectors. However, its cameras and engineers soon began to travel to cover events worldwide. After acquiring Universal Broadcast Systems, the company established a national closed circuit television network.
The company steadily grew in size; by 1990 it housed two divisions: Communication Systems Group-CSG (a company that designs telecommunication systems), and GTN (the production and post-production facility). The physical expansions occurred well into the 1990s, adding a library, Combermere Stage, and various additions to the headquarters in Oak Park, Michigan.
The company has won several awards. Joan Akers Binkow, owner of the company and chair of the board of directors, was named one of Michigan's Top 25 Business Women in 1994.
The record group consists of five series: Administrative Records, History/Background, Organizational Albums, Visual Materials, and Sound Recordings. The record group primary strength lays in documenting a Detroit-based television company's daily activities.
Subjects:
Closed-circuit television--Michigan.; General Television Network.; Telecommunication--Michigan.; Television--Production and direction--Michigan.; Television advertising--Michigan.; Television broadcasting--Michigan.
Genre Terms:
DVDs.; Photographs.; Sound recordings.
- Administrative Records 1958-1997
  The Administrative Records documents some of the daily operations of GTN, its staff. The series includes some correspondence, as well as company advertisements, and newsletters.
  - Facilities (Box 1)
  - Advertisements (Box 1)
  - Advertisements (Box 12)
    (Oversized material)
  - Advertisements (Volume 1)
  - Rates (Box 1)
  - Invoices October 1965-September 1966 (Box 1)
  - Personnel (Box 1)
  - Correspondence
    - Saul Shiefman 1958-1961 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters (Post Script and The Communicator), 1982-1997 (Box 1)
  - Competitors' Information (Box 1)
- History/Background 1958-1996
  The History/Background series consists largely of albums containing newspaper and magazine clippings about the firm.
  - Written 1957-1996 (Box 1)
  - Awards (Box 1)
  - Clippings
    - Boxing 1960-1961, 1 folders (Box 1)
    - Sports 1958-1959, album (Box 1)
    - General 1959-1961, 1 folders (Box 1)
    - 1960-1962 (Box 2)
      (in binder, includes, advertisements, conventions, awards, etc.)
    - 1957-1979 (Box 2)
      (in album labeled 'photographs', includes closed-circuit television brochures, articles, video tape information, etc.)
    - 1976-1983 (Box 2)
      (in album labeled 'Photos', includes letters, brochures, 25 years of GTN, etc.)
- Organizational Albums 1957-1997
  The Organizational Albums series comprises the bulk of the record group. The series begins with a subseries of albums maintained by GTN in roughly chronological order. These volumes are followed by albums documenting GTN social events and the production facilities of GTN. These albums include many photographs, but also transcripts of programs, clippings, and correspondence.
  - Chronological
    - 1957-1958 (Box 3)
      (contains photographs, transcripts, clippings, and correspondence from various programs and initiatives hosted at or filmed by GTN (or using their equipment) during 1957-1958, e.g. closed circuit coverage at the National Open Golf Tournament, football games, etc.)
    - 1959, part 1 (Box 3)
      (contains photographs, transcripts, clippings, and correspondence from various programs and initiatives hosted at or filmed by GTN (or using their equipment) during 1959, e.g. a dental operation, a closed circuit television training course given by the Army Armor School in Fort Knox, etc.)
    - 1959, part 2 (Box 3)
      (contains photographs, transcripts, clippings, and correspondence from various programs and initiatives hosted at or filmed by GTN (or using their equipment) during 1959, e.g. Home Builders Association, "Juvenile Court" series, etc.)
    - 1960-1965 (Box 4)
      (contains photographs, transcripts, clippings, and correspondence from various programs and initiatives hosted at or filmed by GTN (or using their equipment) during 1960-1965, e.g. Detroit Speedway, National Association of Hairdressers, Beauticians, and Fashion Designers, etc.)
    - 1961-1969 (Box 4)
      (contains photographs, transcripts, clippings, and correspondence from various programs and initiatives hosted at or filmed by GTN (or using their equipment) during 1961, e.g. Paray conducting the Detroit Symphony Orchestra at the Jewish Center, filming in a classroom, etc.)
    - 1970-1979 (Box 4)
      (contains photographs, transcripts, clippings, and correspondence from various programs and initiatives hosted at or filmed by GTN (or using their equipment) during 1970-1979, e.g. Knuckle replacement surgery, American Health Spas, etc.)
    - 1985-1989 (Box 5)
      (contains photographs, transcripts, clippings, and correspondence from various programs and initiatives hosted at or filmed by GTN (or using their equipment) during 1985-1989, e.g. Max the Bull Ford Automotive, Get Up and Go Health Tapes, etc.)
    - 1985-1986 "GTN Construction June 1985 to June 1986", slides (Box 5)
    - 1984-1996 (Box 5)
      (contains photographs, transcripts, clippings, and correspondence from various programs and initiatives hosted at or filmed by GTN (or using their equipment) during 1984-1996 e.g. Video Show, Communication Systems Group, etc.)
    - 1990-1994 (Box 6)
      (contains photographs, transcripts, clippings, and correspondence from various programs and initiatives hosted at or filmed by GTN (or using their equipment) during 1990-1994 e.g. Buick Know How, construction of site, Boy Scouts of America, shoot in Miami, FL, etc.)
    - 1995-1997 (Box 6)
      (contains photographs, transcripts, clippings, and correspondence from various programs and initiatives hosted at or filmed by GTN (or using their equipment) during 1995-1997 e.g. Lunar eclipse viewing, construction of site, urologic surgery partnership, etc.)
  - Social Functions
    - "1978 Final Playoff Games, GTN vs. Campbell Ewald" (Box 7)
    - 1980s Misc. Events (Box 7)
      (Retirement party, Open House, Grand Prix and Demo Party, etc.)
    - "New Audio for Video Production Suite party," 1991 (Box 7)
    - "The Early Works Film Fest, 1992" (Box 7)
    - "The Early Works Film Fest, 1993" (Box 7)
    - "GTN Picnics 1975-1986" (Volume 2)
  - Facilities
    - "GTN" (Box 8)
      (photos of the inside and outside of the building)
    - "Closed-Circuit Television" (Box 8)
      (various places that CCTV was installed or used during the 1960s)
    - Internal (Box 8)
      (inside views of rooms and equipment)
    - "Meet the Combermere Stage" (Volume 3)
- Visual Materials
  The Visual Materials includes additional photographs and snapshots of events, proofs, some original artwork commissioned by GTN, and a DVD copy of some of the company's "Historical Commercials."
  - Clients and events
    (Photographs and negatives; identifications provided by donor)
    - A.S.O.P.-Medical 1957 (Box 9)
    - American Society of Training Directors 1989 (Box 9)
    - American Veterinarian Medical Association 1960 (Box 9)
    - Ampex Ado 1983 (Box 9)
    - Boston-R. L. Colton (Box 9)
    - Boy Scouts of America 1991 (Box 9)
    - Briggs Stadium 1957 (Box 9)
    - Buddy's Appliance Store (Box 9)
    - Cerebral Palsy Benefit 1954 (Box 9)
    - Chevy 1961 (Box 9)
    - Chicago Pneumatic (Box 9)
    - Colton, Richard L. (Box 9)
    - Delco-Remy 1961 (Plant Tour for SAE Convention) (Box 9)
    - Dental (Box 9)
    - Dove (Commercial) (Box 9)
    - Film Fest 1993 (Box 9)
    - Football 1958 (M-MSU, OSU-NW, OSU-IOWA) (Box 9)
    - Franklin Hills Cocktail Party, Wrigley Stores promo 1959 (Box 9)
    - GTN-Test Patterns (Box 9)
    - GTN Truck Interior (Box 9)
    - Handleman Filmworks 1986 (Box 9)
    - Hudson's Christmas 1981 (Box 9)
    - Industrial Plants Corp 1959 (Auction) (Box 9)
    - JVS-JWS Community Workshop 1957 (Box 9)
    - Medical, CCTV (Box 9)
    - Meilink 1959 (Box 9)
    - Michigan Credit Union League (Box 9)
    - Michigan International Speedway 1980 (Box 9)
    - Minetola, Shelia 10/20 (Box 9)
    - Misc. Production Shots, 13225 Capital (Box 9)
    - Motorama 1956 (Box 9)
    - N.A.H. B&F Shows (Hairdressers et. al) 1958 (Box 9)
    - Nardin Park Church 1955 (Box 9)
    - National Association of Hairdressers, Beauticians, & Fashion Designers 1960 (Box 9)
    - National Open Golf Tournament, Toledo 1958 (Box 9)
    - Opus Ad Campaign 1989 (Box 9)
    - Orchard's Children's Services Fundraiser (Box 9)
    - Owens Corning Fibreglass 1959 (Box 9)
    - Palmer, George 1960(Giantview Installation) (Box 9)
    - Panacam 1983 (Box 9)
    - Pinkies Storyboard, Dow Corning Commercial 1959 (Box 9)
    - Real Time Steady Transfer 1989 (Mark Piechan, Doug Check, Frank Smith) (Box 9)
    - Rhode Island Auditorium 1958 (Box 9)
    - River Shots of Boats (Box 9)
    - Roberts-Neil, Inc (Before UBS) (Box 9)
    - Special Olympics 1992 (Box 9)
    - Strand Steel (Box 9)
    - Studio views 1976-1977 (Box 9)
    - System Installations 1960s-1970s (Box 9)
    - Those Amazing Animals 1981 (Box 9)
    - Traveling Pictures Animation Company (Box 9)
    - UBS Detroit (Box 9)
    - UBS (Emerson College, Muntz TV, Pontiac/Chrysler, Yale) (Box 9)
    - UBS Premises & Equipment (Box 9)
    - Udylite 1959 (Box 9)
    - Visual Materials, Other UM, Clients, Kelvinator (Box 9)
    - Wayne State 1960 (Box 9)
    - WNTR 1972 (Box 9)
  - Artwork, 1 folders (Box 10)
  - Artwork (Box 12)
  - Proofs (Box 10)
    (contained in individually labeled envelopes)
  - Proofs (Box 12)
  - Negatives (Box 10)
  - Photographs
    - Head Shots (Box 10)
    - Celebrity Portraits, 1 folders (Box 10)
      (most signed by the person)
    - Facility (Box 10)
  - Loose Photographs (Box 11)
    (unprocessed: includes snapshots of holiday parties, social functions, head shots, the facilities, etc.)
  - "General Television Network Historical Commercials", DVD (Box 11)
- Sound Recordings
  The Sound Recordings consists of audio-cassettes of interviews with individuals discussing the history of the company.
  - Charley Abney interview about the history of GTN 1996, 2 audiocassettes (Box 11)
  - John Mayer interview about the history of GTN 1997, 2 audiocassettes (Box 11)
  - "GTN: Introducing DG Systems Network for Broadcast Advertising", 2 audiocassettes (Box 11)